Guide to the First Unitarian Church of Ithaca, New York records, 1861-1986.
First Unitarian Church of Ithaca, New York records, 1861-1986.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
First Unitarian Church of Ithaca, New York records, 1861-1986.
4590
First Unitarian Church (Ithaca, N.Y.).
15.3 cubic ft.
Constitutions, board minutes, correspondence, financial records, and other records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Constitutions, board minutes, correspondence, financial records, and numerous other records of the church.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Constitutions, board minutes, correspondence, financial records, and numerous other records of the church.
SUBJECTS
Names:
First Unitarian Church (Ithaca, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Unitarians--New York (State)--Ithaca.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Box 14 is restricted.
CONTAINER LIST
- Friarworks: About Boards and Committees, by R. Fulghum, 1983? (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Prose piece written by Robert L. Fulghum, Executive Director, Pacific Northwest District
- "George Lincoln Burr" by Henry Guerlac, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Essay written apropos of: George Lincoln Burr, by Roland H. Bainton" reprinted from ISIS, No. 100, Spring of 1944.
- V.D.'s Stories as Told by Virgil D. Morse - 1861-1937., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Bound typescript volume, Compiled by Lillian Shaben and Robert V. Morse. Signed, "Presented to the First Unitarian Society of Ithaca, by Robert V. Morse, Dec. 1945"
- Mendon W. Smith - Perspectives, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Bound volume. "These essays portray my slow attempt to understand the world of history and international politics."
- Board of Trustees - Minutes, March 13, 1900-May 5, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Board Minutes, October 6, 1903-October 7, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Bound manuscript volume with Constitution of 1871 and Board Minutes 1903-1913.
- Board Minutes, 1914-1917 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Bound manuscript volume of Board Minutes 1914-1917.
- Board Minutes, October 2-November 4, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Bound manuscript volume of Board Minutes Oct-Nov 1917
- Correspondence, Board Minutes, Reports, December 1875-June 1920 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Correspondence, Board Minutes, Reports
- Board Documents, July 1920-June 1922 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Board Documents, July 1922-June 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Board Documents, 1926-1929 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Unitarian Service Pension society, Proposed Amendment to Constitution Dec 28, 1928
- Board Documents, September 1929-June 1931 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Board Documents, July 1931-June 1932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Board Documents, July 1932-June 1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Board Documents, August 1941-June 1943 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  AUA Resolution on Anti-Semitism
- Board Documents, September 1943-June 1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Board Documents, October 1946-June 1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Resolution of impartiality by Morse, R.V. 1947; List of Wills 1946, Excerpts from by-laws of AUA
- Board Documents, September 1948-June 1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  R.E. Program, Excerpts from AUA By-Laws, Proposed union between Universalists and Unitarians, Proposals for democratizing structure of AUA, Displaced persons Committee and interpreters, USC Appeal, AUA Resolutions May 1950
- Board Documents, October 1950-June 1951 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Heizer Club, Copy of Section 164, Religious Corporations Law June 1951
- Board Documents, September 1951-June 1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Proposed revision of by-laws Oct 1951, Resolution Nov 5 1951, Constitution as amended to Jan 4 1952, UU Commission on Federal Union Mar 12 1952, Church expansion discussions
- Board Documents, October 1952-June 1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Resolution regarding religion and politics by R.V. Morse Mar 2 1953, Constitution as amended to Apr. 23, 1953
- Board Documents, July 1953-June 1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Church expansion committee report, letters regarding radio sermons
- Board Documents, October 1954-June 1955 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Church as emergency hospital Oct 1954Church expansion report Jan 3 1955, Parish list Jan 1955
- Board Documents, October 1955-June 1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Constitution as amended to Apr. 23, 1957
- Board Documents, July 1957-June 1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Letter re: international assoc. for religious freedom Nov 1957; Letter re: building new church, April 23 1958; Letter re: Parsonage, Apr. 23, 1958; Consideration of Teele House, Apr. 23 1958
- Board Documents, July 1958-June 1959 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  New Parish house, expansion fund, pulpit committee, statement on merger of Unitarians with Universalists
- Board Documents, July 1959-June 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Board Documents, August 1960-June 1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Board Documents, July 1961-June 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Board Documents, July 1962-June 1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Board Documents, July 1963-June 1964 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Hazel's Backyard
- Board Documents, July 1964-June 1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Board Documents, July 1965-June 1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  China Study Group
- Board Documents, September 1966-June 1967 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Board Documents, August 1967-June 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Parlor Project
- Board Documents, July 1968-June 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Board Documents, July 1969-June 1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Board Documents, July 1970-June 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Tompkins County Day Care
- Board Documents, July 1971-June 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Board Documents, July 1972-December 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Board Documents, Jan.-June 1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Grant Proposal to Universalists; New Organ Funding
- Board Documents, July 1973-June 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Final Report to Universalists re: Program for Developing Contemporary Music; Festival of Music Project
- Board Documents, July 1974-June 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Proposal to VEATCH Committee
- Board Documents, July 1975-June 1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Alma Russell Garden
- Board Documents, July 1976-June 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Board Documents, July 1977-June 1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Copy of Tax Exemption Letter of 1962; Constitution as Amended May 23, 1978
- Board Documents, July 1978-June 1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  PARKIT
- Board Documents, July 1979-June 1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Sabbatic Leave; Planning and Development Study
- Board Documents, July 1980-June 1981 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Military Draft Counseling; Church Bond Resolution; Goals Checklist
- Board Documents, July 1981-June 1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Board Documents, July 1982-June 1983 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Board Documents, September 1983-June 1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Board Documents, October 1984-June 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Board Documents, August 1985-June 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Architectural Drawings - Church, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Assessment Material, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Church Roof, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Bids for Roof work; Drawing of Roof
- Contracts, 1980, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Painting Contract 1980; Roof Repairs Contract 1983
- Emergency Evacuation Instructions, Parish House and Church Basement, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Answering Service, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Direct-Page Communications Cost Increase Letter, 1980
- Heating and Insulation, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Reports, Contracts and Bids for heating and insulation work, 1980
- Maintenance and Repairs (1966, 1968, 1970-1976, 1978-1982), 1966-1982 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Building and Grounds; Building Permits; Maintenance Reports
- Parish (Teele) House (1958-1963; 1967, 1977), 1958-1977 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Rental Agreements; Day Care
- Parsonage: 407 E. Buffalo St, 1918-1958 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Abstract of the Title and Deeds to 407 E. Buffalo St.
- Parsonage: 212 Fall Creek Dr., 1958-1971 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Appraisal and Sale of 212 Fall Creek Drive
- Real Estate Transactions, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Summary Report of 1958 Real Estate Transactions for 407 E. Buffalo; 212 Fall Creek Drive; 306 N. Aurora Street
- Church Rental Policies and Contracts, 1970-1984 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  Policies for Use and Rental of Church
- Church Repairs, Bathroom Installation, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Church Safety and Insurance Requirements, 1959-1976 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  Reports about Church Safety Systems; 1973 proposal from Simplex Time Recorder Co. for Smoke, Heat and Fire Detection Equipment.
- Security and Keys, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  In response to thefts at the church, tighter security and more control over building keys was instituted.
- Sound System, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Master Copy of Form, "Using the Sound System"
- Steeple, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  Contracts and Bid Proposals for Steeple Repair Work.
- Bookkeeping Records, 1971, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Capital Development Bond, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  Bond Resolution, Nov 11 1980; Mortgage Agreement
- Finance Committee, 1961-1981 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  Finance Committee Reports
- Finance Committee, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  Insurance Claims
- Finance Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  Other Income Possibilities
- Finance Committee, 1922, 1923, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  Pledges
- Finance Committee, 1943-1974 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  Pledge Campaign
- Finance Committee, 1975-1983 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Property Maintenance Estimates, 1957-1968 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Finance Committee, 1920, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  Treasurer's Books (Bound) 2; Each book contains unbound list of contributing members
- Committees (1921-1928, 1957-1972, 1979-1983), 1921-1983 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  List of Members and Rules for Committees
- Minister's Advisory Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Pulpit Search Committee, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  Photo of Harold Scott
- Pulpit Search Committee, 1958-1961 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  Correspondence and Pending Candidates
- Pulpit Search Committee, 1962, 1965, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Pulpit Search Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  UUA Unitarian Universalists Ministers Association: Guidelines; Meeting minutes 1970; Profile for New Minister 1970; Candidate statements
- Sabbatical and Leave Planning Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Social Concerns Committee, 1961-1968 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Staff - Membership Staffing and Committee, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  Minutes of January 13, 1981 meeting.
- Sunday Program Committee, September 1970-June 1971 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Volunteer Coordinating Committee, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  Requests for Volunteers, 1982
- Worship, Music and Art Committee, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  Reports on Service for Dec 13, 1970
- Area Congregations Together; Meals on Wheels; Kitchen Cupboard (1982-1983; 1981-1982; 1982-1984) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Copies of Unitarian with notices of activities; Annual program for ACT 1982
- Church as Polling Place, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Letter from Ithaca City Clerk about the Church as a Polling Place in 1980.
- Day Care (1967-1970; 1978-1984), 1967-1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Energy Audit Report 1984.
- Draft Counseling, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Information and letters concerning establishment of a Draft Counseling center if the US Senate approved a Peacetime Draft.
- Emergency Outreach Service, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Explanatory circular on the EOS. Names Hazel Brampton, church member.
- Federation of Churches of Ithaca and Vicinity, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Letter and copy of the Constitution of the Federation of Churches of Ithaca and Vicinity.
- Ithaca Council of Church Women, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Program for the Ithaca Council of Church Women, World Day of Prayer, Service at Unitarian Church March 8, 1957.
- PARKIT, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Prevent Alcohol Related Killings and Injuries in Tompkins County - circular listing church members.
- Sponsor of Tompco Better Housing Inc. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Letter accepting Unitarian Church as sponsor of the program. Booklets from Tompso B.H. program.
- Tompkins County Council of Churches, 1966, 1967, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Tompkins County Ministers' Association, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Vietnamese Refugees - Correspondence, June 1975-June 1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Vietnamese Resettlement Report, June 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Vietnamese Refugees - Finances, June 1975-June 1978 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Vietnamese Refugees - Miscellaneous, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Vietnamese Refugees - Publicity, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Vietnamese Refugees - In Town: Names and Needs, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Vietnamese Refugees - Families No Longer Requesting Ithaca Sponsorship, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Vietnamese Refugees - Sponsorship Information, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Vietnamese Refugees - Unitarian Sponsorship, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Vietnamese Refugees - Welcoming Committee: Members, Minutes, Misc., Housing, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Denominational Affairs: College Centers Student Conference and Billings Lecture, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- General Assembly In Ithaca, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Unitarian Universalist Goals Questionnaire, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Minister On Loan Program, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Mohawk Valley Conference (1925, 1941, 1946, 1949), 1925-1949 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- St. Lawrence Unitarian Universalist District (SLUUD), 1963-1968 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- College Centers Committee, 1963-1968 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- SLUUD, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- SLUUD Directory, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Star Island, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Unirondack: Goals and By-laws, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Unitarian Service Committee (USC), 1949 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Unitarian Universalist Service Committee (UUSC), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- History: Alma Russell's Recollections Of Church From 1931. Audio Tape and Transcription., 1988 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Applications For Aid From American Unitarian Association (A.U.A.), 1925-1926 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- History, Description, Constitution and Committees In Booklet Form By Badger, Henry (Pastor), 1881 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Ethical Section Of Unity Club Minutes, 1896-1897 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Music Account, 1897-1898 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- History of Unitarianism In Ithaca, 1865-1965 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- History By: Grinnell, Lawrence, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- History By: Barr, Kate L., 1926 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- History: Highlights In Church History, 1853-1883 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- More Highlights, no date (Box 5, Folder 36)
- History By Mack, Horace, no date (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Historical Notes By Hanford, Rodney (Sexton), no date (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Our Church History By Muenscher, Minner, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Letter From Horace Mack's Granddaughter: Fernow, Lucy Kephart, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- More Historical Notes, no date (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Highlights of History, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Facsimile Of Letter By Bellows, Dr., 1865 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Map Showing Location Of First Building, 1873-1893 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Unitarian Universalist Merger Material, 1932, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- List Of Ministers, 1866-1942 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Church Fire References, 1893-1894 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Eliot, Samuel A. At Sage Chapel, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Seventy Fifth Anniversary, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Banquet Program and Menu, October 16, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Church Service, October 15, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- "How The Foundations Were Laid" By Hosner, Ralph S., October 16, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Lists Of Names For Ithaca and Out Of Town (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Write-Up From Unitarian Magazine (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Sponsorship Of Displaced Persons Families In Ithaca. Audio Cassette Tape and Transcription. (Updated 1992), 1949 (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Outline--Liberal Religious Organization In Tompkins County, 1828-1958 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Historical Sketch and Comments, 1919, 1940? (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Bosworth Fire, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- One Hundredth Birthday Celebration, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Membership: Questionnaires, Promotions (1956, 1957, 1968-1969), 1956-1969 (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Correspondence, Programs (1971-1975, 1978), 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Questionnaires, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 50)
- New Members, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 51)
- New Members - Name Tags, Breakfast, News, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 52)
- Membership Record, 1887-1901 (Box 5, Folder 53)
- Membership Transfers, 1915, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 54)
- Miscellaneous: Certificates and Awards, 1960-1982 (Box 5, Folder 55)
- Choral Reading, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 56)
- Guest Books (2) (1947-1976, 1976-1981), 1947-1981 (Box 5, Folder 57)
- Lexicon, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 58)
- Peter's Birthday Party, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 59)
- Miscellaneous: Singles Group, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Resource Persons, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Cornell University Student Project--Unitarian Church, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Music: Hymnals (shelved) (1869, 1873, 1903, 1914, 1928, 1935, 1937, 1942, 1955), 1869-1955 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Congregational Singing, 1887 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Carols and Songs, Music Folio, Miscellaneous Songs, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Organ and Music, 1928, 1971-1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Organizations: Family and Individual Resource Support Team (F.I.R.S.T.) (1979-1980, 1982-1983), 1979-1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Fortnighters, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Laymen's League Reports, 1924-1931 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Constitution and By-laws, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Chapter Officer's Book, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Men's Egg and Steak Society (MESS), 1975, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Operations Group, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Play and Poetry Readers, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Directory of Organizations (1952-1955, 1965-1967, 1968-1969), 1952-1969 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Religious Education: Adult Education, 1966-1967, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Adult Religious Education, Fall 1982 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Junior Board of Trustees, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Sunday School Reports (1924, 1925, 1936, 1937, 1939, 1946, 1948-1950), 1924-1950 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Church School Reports, October 1950-June 1953 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Religious Education Committee Reports, Programs, Budgets, September 1953-June 1957 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Religious Education Committee Reports, Programs, Budgets, August 1957-June 1959 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Religious Education Committee Reports, Programs, Budgets, September 1959-June 1962 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Religious Education Committee Reports, Programs, Budgets, September 1962-May 1965 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Religious Education Committee Reports, Programs, Budgets, September 1965-June 1966 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Religious Education Committee Reports, Programs, Budgets, August 1965-June 1967 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Religious Education Committee Reports, Programs, Budgets, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Religious Education Committee Reports, Programs, Budgets, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Religious Education Committee - Reports, Programs, 1969-1973 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Religious Education Committee Reports, 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous, Programs, 1975-1983 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Sunday School Book Loan Record, 1904 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Sunday School Treasurer's Bound Book, 1890-1920 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Includes Library Fund, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Young People's Religious Union (YPRU), 1924-1929 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- YPRU Attendance, 1933-1934, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Liberal Religious Youth Conference Material (LRY), 1958-1961 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- LRY Reports and Miscellaneous (1952-1953, 1958-1973), 1952-1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- LRY Program and Worship Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- LRY, 1965-1969 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Sermonettes for R.E. Classes, 1930s (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Channing-Murray Guest Book, 1955-1958 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Unitarian Students (1926, 1948-1949, 1953-1955, 1957-1959, 1961-1964, 1966-1969, 1972, 1974, 1982), 1926-1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Personnel: CETA Title VI, August 1977-April 1979 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Housekeeper Benjamin Schiave Insurance Claim, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Printer, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Program Associate, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Planning: Long Range Planning Committee, 1966-1979 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Planning and Development, 1956-1980 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Planning and Development Study, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Proposal to Veatch Committee, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Renovation Plans, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Programs: Advant Season, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Art In The Parlor, 1980, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Bio-Medical Ethics, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Booksale, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Diners' Club, 1970, 1979-1983 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Garden Program, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Men's Bake Sale, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Neighborhood Meetings, 1976, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Picnics, 1982-1985 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Plant Sale, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Program Planning (1973, 1975-1976, 1981, 1983), 1973-1983 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Retreats, mid-1970s, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Seminar, Spring 1978 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Service Auction, 1980, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Special Dinners, 1977-1985 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Special Programs (1972-1974, 1976, 1981-1982, 1983), 1972-1983 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Synergetic Star: Copyright, Explanation, Directions, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Volunteer Recognition Sundays, Dinners and Parties, 1980-1984 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Wednesday Night Suppers, 1966-1972 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Publications: Church Brochures, 1940-1970s (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Media Releases, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Ithaca Business Directory; Fair of Unitarian Society, 1866 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Kindly Light (Newsletter), December 24, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Kindly Light 2 volumes (bound), 1892-1894 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Unitarian Bulletin (issued by Unitarian Club), January-April 1919 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Postcard Newsletters (15) (1923-1932, 1942-1943), 1923-1943 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Calendar (3), 1936-1938 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Thought For The Week (24 3x5 cards), January-November 1944 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Bound Unitarian (April 6, 1944-December 31, 1945), 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Bound Unitarian, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Bound Unitarian, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Bound Unitarian, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Bound Unitarian, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Bound Unitarian, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Bound Unitarian, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Bound Unitarian, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Bound Unitarian, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Unitarian, January 3-June 20, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Bound Unitarian, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 33)
- News Bulletin For Church Of The Larger Fellowship By Muenscher, Minnie, Sept. 20, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Unitarian (Aug. 1967, 1968-1969), 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Unitarian, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 36)
- Unitarian, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 37)
- Unitarian, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 38)
- Unitarian, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 39)
- Unitarian, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 40)
- Unitarian, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 41)
- Unitarian, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 42)
- Unitarian, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Unitarian, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Unitarian, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Unitarian, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Unitarian, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Unitarian, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Unitarian, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Unitarian, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Unitarian, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Records: Christenings, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Funeral Records, 1959-1969 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Library Purchases, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Marriage Records (1942-1946, 1959-1961, 1965-1970), 1942-1970 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Unitarian Universalist Association Annual Questionnaire, 1950-1968 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Sermons: Gilbert, Richard S., 1965-1969 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Hamby, Larry, May 16, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Harrington, Vilma, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Helverson, Ralph, 1943-1965 (Box 9, Folder 18)